

ADEAN RESSAN M. LADIA

Full Stack Developer & Systems Architect BS Information Technology in Database Track Mindanao State University, General Santos City

Email: adeanladia0129@gmail.com Contact #: +63 928 3078 936 Eligibility: Civil Service Professional

Online Profile:

- narraressan.github.io/narra/
- www.linkedin.com/in/adean-ladia-930b2012a/

CHARACTER SUMMARY

I started my professional career in 2014. Since then, I have experienced working in various designations such as backend lead developer, frontend developer, and lead architect.

Despite being a full-time employee, I still look for ways to further gain more knowledge about the latest technologies on the field through freelancing.

With my 4-year industry experience, I can design and implement scalable, maintainable, and pragmatic applications with least supervision.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Below are fields I have thoroughly focused for the past years:

- Full Stack Programming including mobile, desktop, and web platforms. Also, I am well versed with on both back and front-end frameworks.
- Database management and big data optimization on both relational and non-relational data storage.
- System architecture and containerization with market grade tools (e.g. Dockers, Kubernetes, and Mesos).

CAREER HISTORY

2018 – PRESENT **BACKEND DEVELOPER** @ DETAIL TECH PH.

www.detailonline.com

Regus Tower, #410, Damos, Lanang

Davao City, Philippines

2018 **BACKEND DEVELOPER** @ THE RESIDES GROUP. ph.linkedin.com/company/the-resides-group

New York, NY

2017 – 2019 **FULL STACK DEVELOPER** @ CORDURO INC. www.corduro.com New York, NY

2016 – 2018 **BACKEND DEVELOPER** @ SAMATOSA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CORP. www.samatosa.com

New York, NY

2016
LECTURER @ ACLC – AMA COMPUTER LEARNING CENTER www.aclcgensan.net
General Santos City, Philippines

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2012 – 2016 **BS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY – DATABASE TRACK**Mindanao State University, GSC

Tambler, General Santos City, Philippines

On the Job Training:

- Web Developer
 - MSU GSC, 2016

Capstone Project:

- WebRTC Integrated Communication System and Respondent Locator Adviser: Vladimir Oliva, Phd Software Eng. Project:
- ANSHS Billing and Fee Collection System Adviser: Laiza L. Limpin, MIT

Scholarships and Grants:

- SMG (Special Muslim Grant) with lowest maintaining GPA of 1.75 per semester
- **SWEEP** (SMART WIRELESS ENGINEERING EDUCATION PROGRAM) granted to only 3 students from Mindanao, and with a lowest maintaining grade of 2.5 per subject
- **PPSA** (Paaral para sa Sarangan) granted to qualified students of Sarangani Province with a maintaining GPA of 2.5

Competitions and Events:

- ICCF (2014 2015)
 - Programming Contestant

- FX (2014 2015)
 - Scoring System Programmer
 - 3D Animator
- PSITS (2015) -
 - 4th Place Winner for Programming Competition
 - 4th Place Winner for Research Paper Presentation
- GreenOvation (2015 National Mobile App Competition)
 - Round 1 Top 100 Finalist
 - Round 2 Top 10 Finalist
- "Kibou Fayah" Documentary Film Awardee (Post Video Editor)
 - MSU-GSC EDUC Film Festival

Achievements:

- Outstanding IT Student of the Year
 - Philippine Society of IT Students
 - MSU-GSC CNSM: Wizards Awards 2016
- 2016 Civil Service Exam Passer

Assumed Designations:

- Appointed IT Student Mentor
 - JITS Student Mentoring Program
- Open Programming Coordinator
 - JITS: IT Week 2016
 - JITS: IT Week 2014
- Programming Dare Admin
 - JITS: IT Week 2016
- Online Election IS Coordinator
 - MSU-GSC BA & A Online Elections 2015

Affiliations:

- BAGWIS Official School's Publication (2013 2014)
 - Layout Artist
 - Videographer
 - Animator
 - Web Developer
- JITS Officer (2014 2016)
 - 3rd year Representative (2014 2015)
 - 4th year Representative (2015 2016)

- SBB Volunteer (2012 – 2013)

2008 - 2012

ALABEL NATIONAL SCIENCE HIGH SCHOOL

Regional Science High School for Region XII Brgy. Maribolan, Alabel, Sarangani Province, Philippines

Achievements:

- Consistent Honor Student
- STEP Participant
 - PowerPoint Presentation Competition 2nd Placer
 - Original Character Design 2nd Placer
 - Cosplay & Team Cosplay 1st Placer
- Division Level Science Camp
 - Poster Making 6th Placer

Thesis:

- Viability of Philippine Calamansi (Citrus Microcarpa) Rind as Biogas Source
 - Best Applied Research
 - Best Research Presenter
 - Best Research Presentation (materials, and visual aids)

Affiliations:

- ANSHS Research Team
- Active Club Members of
 - BSP,
 - YRC,
 - SAKAFIL,
 - etc.

2006 - 2008

DADIANGAS WEST CENTRAL ELEMENTARY

Brgy. Dadiangas Wet, General Santos City, Philippines

2002 - 2006

ALABEL JOHANA MONTESSORI SCHOOL

Brgy. Poblacion, Alabel, Sarangani, Philippines

FREELANCE PROJECTS

2018

DROPSCRAPER

Full Stack Developer www.dropscraper.com

2018

DREAM BIG MEDIA INC.

DATO CMS CONSULTANT

2018

BRICKS APP

Front-end Developer & Consultant www.bricksapp.io

2018

TIO LISTING CHATBOT

Backend Architect & Consultant

2018

T-SHIRT PLATFORM PROJECT

Backend Architect & Consultant

2018

BOOKD

Database Architect & Consultant www.bookd.online

2017

TEMPLATE-TED

Full Stack Developer www.templateted.com

2017

BHS: BIOLOGICAL HEALTH SERVICES

Full Stack Developer www.biologicalhealthservices.com.au

2017

SKEDLUXE

Full Stack Developer

2016

POADIS

Front-end Developer www.poadis.com

2016

MAESTRO

UI/UX Designer

2016

LIGI-DEX by Crazy Ideas 1st SOX Startup Challenge Winner Coach and System Architect

2016

Aerial Surveillance with IP Cam on Commercialized Quad Copters

Programmer

MSU – GSC BSEE Undergraduate Thesis

2016

ONLINE ELECTION & MOBILE MONITORING

Lead Developer and Architect
MSU – GSC BA&A Student Elections

2016

MOBITS

Programmer & Student Mentor JITS I.T. Week - Official Mobile App

2015

OMANSS MOBI

Programmer

CNSM Official Mobile App

2015 - 2016

TEKKIES

Programmer and Animator

2015

HOWE INSURANCE SERVICES, LTD

2D Animator

2015 - 2016

FΧ

Programmer and Animator

2015

BAGWIS – Official School's Publication Layout Artisit / Videographer / Animator / Web Developer Mindanao State University, GSC